{
  "name": "Thai",
  "voice_2": null,
  "number": "1",
  "voice_1": null,
  "introduction": null,
  "pul_elements": [
    {
      "answer": "นี้",
      "question": "this",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nee↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนัง",
      "question": "film, movie",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดู",
      "question": "to look at, to watch",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[duu→], ดูหนังนี้ [duu→ nang↗ nee↑] : Watch this movie."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไป",
      "question": "to go",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซิ",
      "question": "(a particle which conveys urgency, adding an imperative quality)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[si↑], ไปซิ [bpai→ si↑] : Let's go!, ดูนี่ซิ [duu→ nee↘ si↑] : Look here!"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผม",
      "question": "(used by male speakers) I, me",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohm↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กิน",
      "question": "to eat or drink",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gin→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น้ำ",
      "question": "water, liquid",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naam↑], ผมกินน้ำ. [phohm↗ gin→ naam↑] : I drink water."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชอบ",
      "question": "to like",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaawp↘], ผมชอบกินน้ำ. [phohm↗ chaawp↘ gin→ naam↑] : I like to drink water."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เย็น",
      "question": "(of an object) (is) cold",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yen→], ผมชอบกินน้ำเย็น. [phohm↗ chaawp↘ gin→ naam↑ yen→] : I like to drink cold water."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชื่อ",
      "question": "name",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อะไร",
      "question": "(indicating a question) what",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[a↓ rai→], ชื่ออะไร [cheuu↘ a↓ rai→] : What is your name."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คุณ",
      "question": "(singular and plural) you",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoon→], คุณชอบกินอะไร [khoon→ chaawp↘ gin→ a↓ rai→] : What do you like to drink ?"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขอบ",
      "question": "pertaining to thanks",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawp↓], ขอบคุณ [khaawp↓ khoon→] : Thank you."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มาก",
      "question": "very",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maak↘], ขอบคุณมาก [khaawp↓ khoon→ maak↘] : Thanks a lot."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วัน",
      "question": "day",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันนี้",
      "question": "today",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wan→ nee↑], (Notice this + day = today.)"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แข็ง",
      "question": "(is) hard, strong",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaeng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น้ำแข็ง",
      "question": "ice",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nam↑ khaeng↗], (Notice hard + water = ice.)"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เอา",
      "question": "to want, to specify or order",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ao→], ผมเอาน้ำแข็ง [phohm↗ ao→ nam↑ khaeng↗] : I want ice."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อัน",
      "question": "thing, item",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[an→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อันนี้",
      "question": "this thing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[an→ nee↑], เอาอันนี้. [ao→ an→ nee↑] : I want this one."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนึ่ง",
      "question": "one",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neung↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อีก",
      "question": "again, still",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[eek↓], อีกอันหนึ่ง. [eek↓ an→ neung↓] : Another one of these."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขวด",
      "question": "bottle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuaat↓], ขวดน้ำ [khuaat↓ naam↑] : a bottle of water"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แม่",
      "question": "mother",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maae↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แม่น้ำ",
      "question": "river",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maae↘ naam↑], (Notice mother + water = river.)"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เท้า",
      "question": "foot",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaao↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กรุงเทพฯ",
      "question": "bangkok",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[groong→ thaehp↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คลอง",
      "question": "(of water) a canal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khlaawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอง",
      "question": "to support (from below), to place (something) under",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รองเท้า",
      "question": "shoe or shoes, footwear, boot or boots",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→ thaao↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หาด",
      "question": "beach",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดิน",
      "question": "to walk",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เด็ก",
      "question": "child",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dek↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วิ่ง",
      "question": "to run",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wing↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทำไม",
      "question": "why",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→ mai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แรง",
      "question": "(is) strong, powerful, energetic, having energy, hard",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaeng→], คุณแข็งแรง"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉลาด",
      "question": "(is) smart, intelligent, clever",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cha↓ laat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชิม",
      "question": "to taste",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chim→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปากกา",
      "question": "pen",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaak↓ gaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มีด",
      "question": "knife",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meet↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ส้อม",
      "question": "fork",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช้อน",
      "question": "spoon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaawn↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ส้ม",
      "question": "(general) orange, citrus, orange color",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รู้สึก",
      "question": "to feel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอย",
      "question": "a trace, a mark",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอยสัก",
      "question": "a tatoo",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy→ sak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ให้",
      "question": "to give",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลูกค้า",
      "question": "customer",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luuk↘ khaa↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาจจะ",
      "question": "maybe, possibly",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aat↓ ja↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนู",
      "question": "pronoun for kids, servants",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nuu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรียก",
      "question": "to be named, called",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพราะว่า",
      "question": "because",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraw↑ waa↘] difference with เพราะ ???"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทั้งสองอย่าง",
      "question": "both",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้องการ",
      "question": "to need",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtawng↘ gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตอบ",
      "question": "reply",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระเบียง",
      "question": "balcony",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ biiang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝึก",
      "question": "to train",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[feuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อย่างง่าย",
      "question": "simple",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaang↓ ngaai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หวังว่า",
      "question": "to hope",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wang↗ waa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อย่างง่ายดาย",
      "question": "easily",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaang↓ ngaai↘ daai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เหงา",
      "question": "lonely",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จังหวัด",
      "question": "province",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jang→ wat↓] Thailand has 76 provinces"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตำบล",
      "question": "sub-district",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam→ bohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คำ",
      "question": "word",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คำศัพท์",
      "question": "vocabulary",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham→ sap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นักท่องเที่ยว",
      "question": "tourist",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↑ thaawng↘ thiaao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลางวัน",
      "question": "day time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลางคืน",
      "question": "night time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตะลึง",
      "question": "is stupefied",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dta↓ leung→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตัว",
      "question": "self",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลิ่น",
      "question": "odor, smell",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ว่า",
      "question": "that",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ได้ยินมาว่า",
      "question": "i have heard that",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขี้อาย",
      "question": "to be shy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขำ",
      "question": "is amused, funny",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัวเราะ",
      "question": "to laugh",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บันดาล",
      "question": "to inspire",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แรงบันดาลใจ",
      "question": "inspiration, muse",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนังสือ",
      "question": "book",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนังสือพิมพ์",
      "question": "newspaper",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถูก",
      "question": "true, correct",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิมพ์",
      "question": "to type",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผิด",
      "question": "wrong, incorrect",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิมพ์ผิด",
      "question": "to type wrong",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "2อาทิตย์ต่อปี",
      "question": "2 weeks per year",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คุก",
      "question": "jail",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉิบหาย",
      "question": "damn!",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้น",
      "question": "tree",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้นสัก",
      "question": "teak tree",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บ้านนอก",
      "question": "countryside",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาดำ",
      "question": "rice paddy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปาก",
      "question": "mouth or any part in the mouth",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผม",
      "question": "hair (of the head)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohm↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น้อย",
      "question": "(is) little, small",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawy↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ก็",
      "question": "(a particle or conjunction that emphasizes that which follows)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หวาน",
      "question": "(is) sweet",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชีพ",
      "question": "life, existence, living",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheep↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไกล",
      "question": "(is) far, distant",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใกล้",
      "question": "(is) near, close",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมา",
      "question": "(is) drunk, intoxicated",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาที",
      "question": "a minute",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaM thee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กี่",
      "question": "how many",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gee↓], กี่นาที : How many minutes ?"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใช่",
      "question": "yes, I agree, correct, right, indeed, that's so",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลืม",
      "question": "to forget",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuum→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นม",
      "question": "milk, a woman's breast",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จูบ",
      "question": "to kiss",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[juup↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นก",
      "question": "bird",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nohk↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วัด",
      "question": "temple, monastery",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wat↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปลา",
      "question": "fish",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสร็จ",
      "question": "(is) finished, completed, ready",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[set↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แต่",
      "question": "but, even, however, rather",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaae↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช้าง",
      "question": "elephant, pachyderm, Elephas maximus",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaang↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใน",
      "question": "in, inside, within, amidst, into, on, at a particular time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เอา",
      "question": "to take, get, bring",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดือน",
      "question": "month",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deuuan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แดง",
      "question": "(is) red",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คืน",
      "question": "night",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheuun→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บ่อย",
      "question": "often",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawy↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไก่",
      "question": "chicken",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝน",
      "question": "rain",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fohn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพื่อน",
      "question": "friend, pal, chum, buddy, older colleague",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuuan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หรือ",
      "question": "or",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ได้",
      "question": "can, to be able, is able, am able, may, might (auxiliary of potential, denoting possbility, ability, or permission)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรา",
      "question": "we, us, our",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช้า",
      "question": "(is) slow",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaa↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ห้อง",
      "question": "room of a building, apartment, chamber",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haawng↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สู้",
      "question": "to contend, fight, compete, make an aggressive move",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไม่",
      "question": "not, no",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยุง",
      "question": "mosquito",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoong→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมือง",
      "question": "city, nation, country, land, town",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuuang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดำ",
      "question": "(is) black, dark, dusky",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เล็ก",
      "question": "(is) small, tiny, fine, little",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lek↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มา",
      "question": "to come, <subject> comes",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าว",
      "question": "rice",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โรงเรียน",
      "question": "(general) school (not used to refer to college or university)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hngM riian→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนัก",
      "question": "(is) heavy, laden, fully loaded, weighing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ล้าง",
      "question": "to clean, wash, rinse",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laang↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ป่า",
      "question": "forest, woods, jungle, wild",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaa↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาว",
      "question": "(is) white",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกิด",
      "question": "to be born, to birth, to happen",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[geert↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตา",
      "question": "eye",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เช่น",
      "question": "similar to, same as",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุญ",
      "question": "holy, virtuous, pure, sacred",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boon→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยัง",
      "question": "yet, since, not yet, still",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทำ",
      "question": "to do or perform an action, to cause or effect a result",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พบ",
      "question": "to meet or rendezvous, locate, find, encounter, experience, discover",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohp↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชั่วโมง",
      "question": "(in time, of time) an hour (when used as a quantity)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaaF mo:hng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พี่",
      "question": "older sibling, older siblings",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phee↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลม",
      "question": "air, wind, storm, breeze",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รัก",
      "question": "to love, <subject> loves",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คอ",
      "question": "neck, throat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaw→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยาก",
      "question": "(is) difficult, hard, not easy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นักเรียน",
      "question": "student, pupil (thru high school), schoolchildren",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nakH riian→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มือ",
      "question": "hand, hands",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เงิน",
      "question": "money, finance, silver",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมา",
      "question": "dog",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกล้า",
      "question": "head, mind",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครู",
      "question": "teacher, instructor",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khruu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โชค",
      "question": "luck",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cho:hk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รถ",
      "question": "car, vehicle, bus",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[roht↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปิด",
      "question": "to close, turn off, to shut",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไฟ",
      "question": "fire, flame",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกาะ",
      "question": "island",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คิด",
      "question": "to think, consider, imagine, expect, compute, to count, wonder",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เป็น",
      "question": "to be, <subject> is",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยา",
      "question": "drug, medicine, remedy, medication, having to do with medical treatment",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยาว",
      "question": "(of geometric length) (is) long",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร้อน",
      "question": "(of temperature) (is) hot",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawn↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาน",
      "question": "long time, as time passes",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นั่น",
      "question": "there (at a medium distance from here), those, that",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมู่",
      "question": "Moo (part of a street address in Thailand), neighborhood, block",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muu↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กว่า",
      "question": "(suffix used for comparisons) than, more, -er",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gwaa↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แปลก",
      "question": "(is) strange, unusual, queer, weird, peculiar, odd, curious",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaaek↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซื้อ",
      "question": "to buy or purchase",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuu↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อากาศ",
      "question": "weather, air, climate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM gaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครอบครัว",
      "question": "family",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraawpF khruaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชาย",
      "question": "male",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภูเขา",
      "question": "hill, mountain",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM khao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โต๊ะ",
      "question": "table",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dto↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เหมือน",
      "question": "(is) similar, all the same, like, as",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuuan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กะ",
      "question": "to, with, also",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ga↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไหน",
      "question": "(used as a question) which, where, when",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข่าว",
      "question": "news, tidings, information received, message",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "งู",
      "question": "snake",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nguu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถ้า",
      "question": "(indicating a condition) if",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นิยม",
      "question": "(is) popular",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[niH yohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เนื้อ",
      "question": "beef, flesh, tissue meat of any animal (especially) meat of the cow",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neuua↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อยาก",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb) to want, desire, crave for",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร้าน",
      "question": "store or shop, commercial establishment, a place where merchandise is sold",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แก่",
      "question": "(of a person or animal) (is) old, aged",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaae↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น้ำมัน",
      "question": "oil, gasoline, fuel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[namH man→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฟัน",
      "question": "tooth",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขา",
      "question": "(of a human, chair, tripod, etc.) leg, lower extremities",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาษา",
      "question": "language(s), speech, idiom, tongue, lingo, understanding, words",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM saa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถูก",
      "question": "(a verb particle reflecting passive voice)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมีย",
      "question": "wife",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[miia→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อวบ",
      "question": "chubby",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โรง",
      "question": "building, hall, pavilion, structure, theater",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คะ",
      "question": "(word added by a female speaker to the end of every question to convey politeness)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kha↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แน่",
      "question": "(is) sure, certain, truthful, firm, stable, without doubt, exact",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naae↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาย",
      "question": "to sell",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "งาน",
      "question": "work, job, duty, business, function",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หญิง",
      "question": "female",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไข่",
      "question": "egg",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พ่อ",
      "question": "father",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เร็ว",
      "question": "(is) fast, quick, speedy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reo→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไทย",
      "question": "Thai, of or pertaining to Thailand",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฟัง",
      "question": "to listen, listen to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นิด",
      "question": "(is) tiny, very small, microscopic",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อ้วน",
      "question": "(is) fat, overweight, not thin",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[uaan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กับ",
      "question": "with, to, for",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทะเล",
      "question": "sea",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH laeh→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนู",
      "question": "mouse, mice, rat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nuu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แพง",
      "question": "(is) expensive",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลูก",
      "question": "child, offspring, son or daughter (including figurative usage for certain ideas), cub, young animal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luuk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผี",
      "question": "ghost, spirit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phee↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เปล่า",
      "question": "(is) void, empty, naked, nothing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดี่ยว",
      "question": "(is) single, alone, sole",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผล",
      "question": "fruit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระดูก",
      "question": "bone",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL duuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "และ",
      "question": "and",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lae↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรียน",
      "question": "to study at the elementary school level",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riian→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัว",
      "question": "head, brain, bulb, tuber",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[huaa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เท่าไร",
      "question": "...how much?... how many?, to that extent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaoF rai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพราะ",
      "question": "because, because of, due to, owing to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraw↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สวย",
      "question": "(is) beautiful, pretty, lovely, gorgeous, attractive, nice-looking (usually referring to women but also possibly a view)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suay↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เช้า",
      "question": "morning, specifically, hours between 6:00 a.m. and 11:00 a.m. or typically 9:00 a.m.",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaao↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จาก",
      "question": "from",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สวัสดีค่ะ",
      "question": "(spoken politely by a female) hello or goodbye",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL watL deeM kha↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นั่ง",
      "question": "to sit or be sitting",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สี่",
      "question": "four, the number or quantity four",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[see↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อ่าน",
      "question": "to read, <subject> reads",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aan↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดี",
      "question": "(is) good, well, fine, nice",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บน",
      "question": "over, above, on, upon, in",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สี",
      "question": "color, colors, paint",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[see↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใจ",
      "question": "heart, spirit, spiritual center or core, soul, inner being, mind",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เจ็บ",
      "question": "(is) sore, hurt, injured, in pain, in emotional pain",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jep↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลัว",
      "question": "(is) afraid (of), scared, frightened",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gluaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สนุก",
      "question": "(is) fun, enjoyable, entertaining, amusing, pleasant",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL nook↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดื่ม",
      "question": "to drink, <subject> drinks",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deuum↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนาว",
      "question": "(feeling) (is) cool, cold",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พูด",
      "question": "to speak, to talk, to say",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuut↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แล้ว",
      "question": "(adverbial word indicating past tense or aspect marker indicating present perfect (past continued to present)) in the past, completed, still, to make done",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laaeo↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาทิตย์",
      "question": "week",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM thit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สอน",
      "question": "to teach, to instruct, to train",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สนใจ",
      "question": "(is) interested (in), (is) attentive (to)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohnR jai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขน",
      "question": "(of the body, but not the head, of a human) hair",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khohn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดียว",
      "question": "(is) single, alone",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รำ",
      "question": "to dance",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ram→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใหญ่",
      "question": "(is) big, large, huge, major, enormous, extensive, sizeable",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประมาณ",
      "question": "approximately, about, roughly",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL maan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทุก",
      "question": "every, each",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thook↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เก้าอี้",
      "question": "chair",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaoF ee↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หู",
      "question": "ear",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[huu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นอน",
      "question": "to sleep, lie down",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมู",
      "question": "pork, meat of the pig",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เป็ด",
      "question": "duck",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดอก",
      "question": "flower",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daawk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หยุด",
      "question": "to stop, halt",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoot↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ห้าม",
      "question": "(is) forbidden, taboo, prohibited, banned",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haam↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บ้าน",
      "question": "house, home, place (or one's place), village",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บางที",
      "question": "maybe, sometimes, perhaps",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baangM thee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไหม",
      "question": "(word added at the end of a statement to indicate a question)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรือ",
      "question": "boat, ship, barge, vessel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuua→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ของ",
      "question": "of, belonging to, that or those of, (a word used with a pronoun to indicate possesion, as in \"John's truck\")",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้อง",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb) has to..., must..., is required to..., is duty-bound to...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtawng↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทอด",
      "question": "(is) deep-fried",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawt↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชา",
      "question": "(general) tea",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขอ",
      "question": "to ask for, to request, \"I'd like...\" — \"May/Can I have...?\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaw↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วัว",
      "question": "cow, ox, bovine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wuaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แกะ",
      "question": "sheep",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gae↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ออม",
      "question": "to conserve, save, economize",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aawm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกวียน",
      "question": "cart, oxcart, wagon (typically) used to transport grain",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gwiian→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หวัง",
      "question": "to hope, to expect, to want",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตาม",
      "question": "according to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สัมมา",
      "question": "right, correct, honest, virtuous, righteous",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR maa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลวง",
      "question": "state (pertaining to the government)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ละ",
      "question": "each, every, one at a time, (implying division) per",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[la↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปรากฏ",
      "question": "to appear, to seem, to reveal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraaM goht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พระ",
      "question": "(a title of ancient Thai civil nobility between พระยา  (Phraya) and หลวง  (Luang))",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phra↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เคลื่อน",
      "question": "to move to another place, to move or relocate in a supervised or organized fashion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khleuuan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราชการ",
      "question": "civil service, public service, government service, bureaucracy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raatF chaH gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สว่าง",
      "question": "(is) bright, shining, illuminated",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL waang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทำลาย",
      "question": "to damage, harm, do harm, destroy, ruin, crush",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thamM laai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เต็ม",
      "question": "(is) complete, full",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtem→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วาน",
      "question": "the day before",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รู้สึก",
      "question": "to feel or emote, to feel an emotion, to experience",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruuH seuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยิ่ง",
      "question": "excessive, extreme",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตำ",
      "question": "to pierce, puncture, prick",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชาติ",
      "question": "national, of a nation, race, of a country",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไหล",
      "question": "(as a liquid) to flow or run, to slither",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยอด",
      "question": "budgetary item, grand total, total",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawt↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อก",
      "question": "(general) breast, chest",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ohk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จำนวน",
      "question": "amount, number, quantity (of countable nouns)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jamM nuaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันพุธ",
      "question": "Wednesday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM phoot↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พยายาม",
      "question": "to attempt, try, persevere, endeavor, make an effort",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaH yaaM yaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชนิด",
      "question": "class, sort, type, variety, category, group, kind, species, in the style of...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaH nit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โคม",
      "question": "lamp, lantern",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kho:hm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บังคับ",
      "question": "to force, compel, command, control, coerce, enforce, compulsory, mandatory",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bangM khap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพิ่ม",
      "question": "to increase, add, grow, advance, boost, develop, enlarge, enhance, escalate, expand, extend, multiply, raise, spread, swell, more",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheerm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วัง",
      "question": "palace",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผู้",
      "question": "person, human, one (who...), (Thai prefix corresponding to the English suffixes) '-er' or '-or'",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เขา",
      "question": "(3rd person singular or plural pronoun) he, she, him, her, they, them",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เท่า",
      "question": "(is) equal, equivalent, even, as much as",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นคร",
      "question": "city, town, municipality",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naH khaawn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขับ",
      "question": "to drive, operate, chauffer",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทุ่ง",
      "question": "field, plain, pasture",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thoong↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กรรมการ",
      "question": "committee, board member",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM maH gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จัก",
      "question": "(is) serrated, notched",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุญ",
      "question": "good deeds, merit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boon→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปลูก",
      "question": "to cultivate, to plant, build, to grow a plant",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpluuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จน",
      "question": "(most commonly used term) (is) poor, penniless, having nothing, impoverished",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[john→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มารดา",
      "question": "mother",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maanM daa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉัน",
      "question": "(used by females in an informal setting—also used by males with intimate friends or lovers) I, me, my",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จบ",
      "question": "end, finale",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถาม",
      "question": "to ask (a question), to inquire, to quiz, to interrogate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaam↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แทน",
      "question": "instead",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทาย",
      "question": "to foretell, prophesy, predict, guess",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อยู่",
      "question": "is (located at), to reside, to live (at), stay, exist at a particular point in time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yuu↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ริม",
      "question": "edge, rim, banks (of a river or canal)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rim→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทราบ",
      "question": "(polite) to know a fact or piece of information",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saap↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ม้า",
      "question": "horse",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maa↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เตรียม",
      "question": "to prepare, to be ready, to ready",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtriiam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เก่า",
      "question": "(of an object) (is) old, antique, decrepit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปวง",
      "question": "in general, as a group, taken together",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpuaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ว่าง",
      "question": "(is) vacant, free, available, empty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระดาษ",
      "question": "paper",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กาง",
      "question": "to unfurl, to open, to stretch out, to spread out",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราคา",
      "question": "price, tariff, fare, cost, (coinage) denomination",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaM khaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉะนั้น",
      "question": "consequently, thus",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL nan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทาบ",
      "question": "to brace or splice with a long piece alongside",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaap↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แท้",
      "question": "(is) genuine, real, true",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaae↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครึ่ง",
      "question": "half, midway, mid, ½",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khreung↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พา",
      "question": "to bring, take, head a procession, lead the way, conduct, show the way, carry, lead people or animals, take along",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพลิน",
      "question": "joyful, joyous, jovial, enjoyable, pleasurable, carried away",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phleern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมฆ",
      "question": "cloud",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maehk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สอง",
      "question": "two, the number or quantity two",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เธอ",
      "question": "(used in intimate or informal settings) you (the 2nd person singular pronoun)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuuhr→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชวน",
      "question": "to persuade, to induce, to urge, to invite, to ask, to influence, to prevail upon, to agree",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลื่อน",
      "question": "to slide, to slip, to glide, to skid",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เบี้ย",
      "question": "a small amount of money",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[biia↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รักษา",
      "question": "to take care of, maintain, save",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rakH saa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทหาร",
      "question": "military, army, soldier",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH haan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตาย",
      "question": "(general) to die, be dead, perish, decease, expire, terminate, pass away, (car) stop (working)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เที่ยว",
      "question": "a trip, vacation, holiday, pleasure tour",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiaao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วิชา",
      "question": "(of study) a subject, knowledge, branch of study",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wiH chaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดุจ",
      "question": "similar to, as if, as though",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[doot↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภายใน",
      "question": "internal, inside",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM nai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกณฑ์",
      "question": "criteria, criterion, formula, specification, standard",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaehn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กิริยา",
      "question": "action, manners, behavior, conduct",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giL riH yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ค่า",
      "question": "value, price, charge, cost, expense",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลัก",
      "question": "to steal, to pilfer, to pinch, to carry off",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าม",
      "question": "across from, opposite",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaam↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แพ้",
      "question": "(is) defeated, lost",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธง",
      "question": "flag",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซื่อ",
      "question": "(is) faithful, loyal, honest",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซ้าย",
      "question": "left direction (opposite of right)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นักปราชญ์",
      "question": "philosopher",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nakH bpraat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชีวิต",
      "question": "life",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheeM wit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โน้น",
      "question": "that one over there, a distant object",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[no:hn↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนี",
      "question": "to escape, elope, hurry away, flee",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nee↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธุระ",
      "question": "business, personal business, errands",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thooH ra↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตอน",
      "question": "a period of time, during..., an interval, when...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คราว",
      "question": "occasion, time, episode",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตั้ง",
      "question": "to decree, lay down, formulate (laws, rules, regulations, questions)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนทาง",
      "question": "way, route, course, path",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohnR thaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จักร",
      "question": "circle, wheel, disk, discus, cycle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อื่น",
      "question": "(is) other",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[euun↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กะ",
      "question": "guess, rough estimate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ga↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ก่อ",
      "question": "to construct, to begin to build",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใส่",
      "question": "to put in, add",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระด้าง",
      "question": "(is) harsh, stiff, rough, coarse, crude, obstinate, rebellious, mutinous",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรม",
      "question": "truth, enlightenment",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขวาง",
      "question": "to obstruct, impede, be in the way of, bar",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เห็น",
      "question": "to see, visualize",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hen↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มิถุนายน",
      "question": "June",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[miH thooL naaM yohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บริบูรณ์",
      "question": "(is) perfect, complete, full, flawless",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawM riH buun→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จริง",
      "question": "truthful, truthfully, really?, true, real, serious, no-nonsense, well, so",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jing→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนี้",
      "question": "debt, liability",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nee↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชี้",
      "question": "to point (out), to indicate a location",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chee↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "to connect",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จง",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb used to indicate a command or order) should, ought to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตัวอย่าง",
      "question": "example, sample",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtuaaM yaang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รบ",
      "question": "to go to war, to fight, to make war, to battle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rohp↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แทน",
      "question": "substitute, replacement, deputized, representative",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทูต",
      "question": "ambassador, diplomat, emissary, envoy, attaché",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuut↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โลก",
      "question": "the world, globe",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lo:hk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยาม",
      "question": "a guard, sentry, sentinel or night watchman",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ส่อง",
      "question": "to illuminate, enlighten, to shine or throw light upon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าศึก",
      "question": "enemy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaF seuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมควร",
      "question": "(is) suitable, proper, fitting, reasonable, appropriate, correct",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR khuaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมาคม",
      "question": "association, organization, corporation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL maaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลา",
      "question": "to say good-bye, to be on leave, to take one's leave, to bid farewell",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลบ",
      "question": "(charge, digit) negative, non-positive",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohp↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยืน",
      "question": "to stand",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yeuun→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภูมิ",
      "question": "earthen land, soil, site, grounds, floor, place",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM mi↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บังเกิด",
      "question": "to beget, produce, engender, conceive, pop up",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bangM geert↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประโยชน์",
      "question": "useful, beneficial",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL yo:ht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ควาย",
      "question": "(general) water buffalo",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไข",
      "question": "open, unfold, explain, unlock, tell, expand",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เตียง",
      "question": "bed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtiiang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คณะ",
      "question": "faculty of a college or university",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaH na↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสาร์",
      "question": "(general) Saturn",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หา",
      "question": "to find, look for, seek, to search",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยนต์",
      "question": "(is) powered, motorized, mechanical",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หาย",
      "question": "to disappear, lose, lost, be missing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เอก",
      "question": "(usually used as an adjective) (is) sole, solitary, single, chief, first, prime, important, leading, excellent, one, alone, lonely",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aehk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมด",
      "question": "(is) empty, finished, all used up, complete, lost",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[moht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขีด",
      "question": "100 grams",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พงศาวดาร",
      "question": "annals, historical record, pedigree, chronicle, dynastic history",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohngM saaR waH daan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปรารถนา",
      "question": "to wish for, to desire",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraatL thaL naa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พลิก",
      "question": "to turn over, to roll from side to side, to play tricks with, to twist",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phlik↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทัพ",
      "question": "army, fighting forces, force, troops, armed forces",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซึ่ง",
      "question": "(the relative pronouns) who, whose, whom, of which",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seung↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขา",
      "question": "(spoken by a female to indicate an affirmative response) \"Yes\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราษฎร์",
      "question": "citizens, population, the people, the populace, the masses",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปี",
      "question": "year, annum, annual",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถ้อย",
      "question": "words, wording, speech, utterance, diction, verbal expression, statement, terms",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawy↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คำ",
      "question": "word, term, discourse",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ออก",
      "question": "the exit, the way out",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aawk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แก้ว",
      "question": "(general) glass, transparent or translucent object, crystal, mica",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaeo↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มี",
      "question": "to have or possess, to be available",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอย",
      "question": "a trace, pathway, track, vestige, impression, imprint, a mark",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันอาทิตย์",
      "question": "Sunday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM aaM thit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สืบ",
      "question": "to search for the facts, to investigate, to detect, to trace, to track",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuup↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร่าง",
      "question": "mesh, structure, grid",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันพฤหัสฯ",
      "question": "(colloquial) Thursday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM phaH reuH hat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บัญญัติ",
      "question": "legal act, law, decree, ordance, regulation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[banM yat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แปด",
      "question": "eight, the number or quantity eight",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaaet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยอม",
      "question": "to allow, yield, let, accept, agree to, is willing to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น่า",
      "question": "(a prefix to a verb or adjective indicating a likely or probable state, as in the English suffix) \"-able\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เผื่อ",
      "question": "in case of, provided that, if, for, in case (that)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuua↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นิ่ง",
      "question": "(is) still, immobile, silent, motionless, quiet",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ning↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สาม",
      "question": "three, the number or quantity three",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saam↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดาว",
      "question": "star, a non-planetary celestial body, spot",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ศาสนา",
      "question": "religion, creed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saatL saL naa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สละ",
      "question": "to abandon, to renounce, to relinquish, to sacrifice, to foresake, to abdicate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL la↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จึง",
      "question": "thus, therefore, so",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jeung→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พื้น",
      "question": "(of a room) floor, foundation, slab, underfloor",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuun↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลวง",
      "question": "to deceive, to gull, to dupe, to impose upon by craftiness or guile, to lure, entice or tempt into some snare or trap",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใหม่",
      "question": "(is) new, modern, fresh",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตำแหน่ง",
      "question": "position, post, rank",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtamM naeng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตรวจ",
      "question": "to check, test, examination, inspection",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtruaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทาน",
      "question": "(formal, yet abbreviated) to eat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชน",
      "question": "(singular) person, (plural) people",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สำราญ",
      "question": "(is) content happy, reveling (in)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR raan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เครื่อง",
      "question": "machine, apparatus, engine, mechanical device",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khreuuang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อ้าง",
      "question": "to claim, claim that",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัน",
      "question": "twist, turn",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พาณิชย์",
      "question": "commerce, pertaining to commerce",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM nit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้า",
      "question": "an attendant, servant, slave, a person under the authority of another",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประตู",
      "question": "door, gate, doorway, entrance",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL dtuu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาฬิกา",
      "question": "timepiece, clock, wristwatch, watch",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaM liH gaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประหลาด",
      "question": "(is) strange, odd, weird, peculiar, wonderful, marvelous, queer, unusual, surprising",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL laat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดิม",
      "question": "the origin, beginning, start",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deerm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แล้ง",
      "question": "(is) dry",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laaeng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาง",
      "question": "woman",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาณาจักร",
      "question": "kingdom, jurisdiction, realm, domain, dominion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM naaM jak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จม",
      "question": "to sink, drown, submerge",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นอกจาก",
      "question": "except, unless, with the exception of..., other than..., besides, not only",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawkF jaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตี",
      "question": "to beat, hit, strike, or whip",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มัน",
      "question": "(the indefinite pronoun for referring to animals or things) it, they",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[man→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หม้อ",
      "question": "small container",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร้อย",
      "question": "hundred, the number one hundred, 100",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กำหนด",
      "question": "a schedule or appointment",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM noht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "งอก",
      "question": "to sprout, bud, grow, shoot off",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaawk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพื่อ",
      "question": "for, on behalf of, for the purpose of...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuua↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แดน",
      "question": "border, land boundary, area, region",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daaen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หน่อย",
      "question": "(word used to soften the meaning of a sentence) \"...a bit\" — \"...somewhat\" — \"...to some extent\", this little thing, no big deal here, for just a moment",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawy↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เนื่อง",
      "question": "(is) due to, related or connected to, a result of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neuuang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาษี",
      "question": "tax, duty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM see↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "telephone extension",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร้าย",
      "question": "(is) bad, very bad, fierce, cruel, harmful, evil, wild",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ควร",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb indicating) should, ought to, must",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถวาย",
      "question": "to give, offer, present",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaL waai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขี่",
      "question": "to ride upon, to drive (an animal, bicycle, or motorcycle)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khee↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โต",
      "question": "(is) big, large, grown",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dto:h→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครับ",
      "question": "(word added by a male speaker to the end of every sentence to convey politeness or) \"yes\", \"that's right\", \"I see.\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กสิกรรม",
      "question": "agriculture",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaL siL gam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุตร",
      "question": "child, offspring, son or daughter",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boot↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จัก",
      "question": "to cleave, split, or serrate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จะ",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb indicating future tense—must be used with another verb) will, shall",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ja↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระลึก",
      "question": "to think of, to recollect, to recall, to remember",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH leuk↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประกาศ",
      "question": "to announce, to proclaim, to declare, to notify, to publish",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝรั่ง",
      "question": "non-Asian foreigner, (usually) Caucasian (see notes)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faL rang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขณะ",
      "question": "instant, moment, a short time, occasion, juncture, hour",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaL na↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รัง",
      "question": "nest, home",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมู่",
      "question": "group, race, flock, herd, crowd, corporation, company, collection, squad, clusters, series, class, genus, rove",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muu↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชน",
      "question": "to collide, to crash, bump, bump together",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ย้าย",
      "question": "to move or transfer",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รับประทาน",
      "question": "to dine, eat, sup, have a meal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rapH bpraL thaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "to battle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทั่ว",
      "question": "all, entire, complete, whole, throughout",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถั่ว",
      "question": "a bean or pea plant, a bean",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuaa↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อัน",
      "question": "item, a small thing, piece",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[an→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "against, towards, to, further, on",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใบ",
      "question": "paper, sheet, card, ticket, document, blade",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กว้าง",
      "question": "(is) wide, broad",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gwaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พุทธ",
      "question": "Buddha",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phoot↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันอังคาร",
      "question": "Tuesday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM angM khaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โอรส",
      "question": "one's own son (legitimate) used by royalty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[o:hM roht↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซึ่ง",
      "question": "(the relative pronouns) that, which",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seung↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประสงค์",
      "question": "to wish or desire",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL sohng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกลา",
      "question": "to form into a rough shape, to trim, to clip (e.g. beard, bush)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตำบล",
      "question": "sub-district, a subdivision of the อำเภอ ",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtamM bohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมอ",
      "question": "(informal) a medical doctor, a fortuneteller, a shaman",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaw↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แน่น",
      "question": "(is) tight, firm, secure",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สด",
      "question": "(is) fresh, green, not spoiled, new, newly produced or minted, raw, (colors) bright",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[soht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แจง",
      "question": "an explanation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาพ",
      "question": "existence, state, being, (a suffix corresponding to the English suffix \"-dom\")",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaap↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัน",
      "question": "active, energetic, vigorous, enthusiastic",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุคคล",
      "question": "person, individual, man, commoner",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bookL khohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พ้น",
      "question": "to pass by, to be beyond, to be clear of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยาม",
      "question": "period of time designated as a shift or a watch for a sentinel or watchman",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มอญ",
      "question": "Mon, Pegu, Peguan, an ethnic group of Burma and Thailand",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไฟ",
      "question": "electric light, light switch",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝัก",
      "question": "hull, pod, sheath, case, nutshell",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พัก",
      "question": "a short while",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อังกฤษ",
      "question": "England, English, Great Britain, British",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[angM grit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คณะ",
      "question": "council, group, member, corporation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaH na↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เชื้อ",
      "question": "bacteria, microbe, yeast, germ",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuua↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กิเลส",
      "question": "lust, evil wish, desire, longing, greed, avarice, rapacity",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giL laeht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แดด",
      "question": "sunlight, sunshine, sun, strong sunlight, rays of the sun",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daaet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สงสาร",
      "question": "feel sorry for, to pity",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR saan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝัง",
      "question": "to bury, inter, put in the ground, implant",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุหรี่",
      "question": "cigarette",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[booL ree↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แทบ",
      "question": "nearly, almost",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaep↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จันทร์",
      "question": "the Moon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัก",
      "question": "to break, be broken off, reflect, tax",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พันธ์",
      "question": "to be related, to bind, to fasten together",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เคย",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb) used to..., did once...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheeuy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตก",
      "question": "to fall, to drop or pour down, to fail",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtohk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วงศ์",
      "question": "lineage, family, dynasty, clan, kinship, descent, stock, race, multitude, assemblage, family (taxonomy)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พาล",
      "question": "to fight or quarrel with, accost, pick a fight with, to bully",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รวม",
      "question": "to combine, collect, add, include, incorporate, assemble, confederate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนังสือ",
      "question": "book, document, letters, alphabet, printed document, written document",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nangR seuu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝึกหัด",
      "question": "to drill, practice, rehearse, to train",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[feukL hat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมื่อ",
      "question": "(indicating a point in time) when, on (a date)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuua↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขอรับ",
      "question": "(very formal polite particle used by a male)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawR rap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หยาบ",
      "question": "(is) rude, vulgar, impolite, obscene",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปรกติ",
      "question": "(is) normal, usual, routine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bprohkL gaL dti↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลิก",
      "question": "to quit, to stop, to give up, cancel, suspend, discontinue, abolish, cease, exit, split up",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leerk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พืช",
      "question": "plant, vegetation, fauna, seedling",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuut↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แสดง",
      "question": "to act, perform, demonstrate, show, or display",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL daaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทัน",
      "question": "to overtake, catch up with, be on time, be abreast of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[than→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมษายน",
      "question": "April",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maehM saaR yohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพลิน",
      "question": "to enjoy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phleern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ศูนย์",
      "question": "zero, the number or quantity zero",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suun↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เชื้อ",
      "question": "flammable fuel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuua↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลว",
      "question": "(is) bad, inferior, worthless, base, vile",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laayo→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กอบ",
      "question": "to scoop up with the hands",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิษ",
      "question": "poison, toxin, venom",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้าน",
      "question": "to resist, oppose, stop, withstand, impede, hinder, (the prefix) anti-",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พฤศจิกายน",
      "question": "November",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phreutH saL jiL gaaM yohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตลาด",
      "question": "market, marketplace",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL laat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มิตร",
      "question": "friend or friends",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นั้น",
      "question": "that one, object at a medium distance, those",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถูก",
      "question": "(is) true, correct, right, conforming",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กรกฎาคม",
      "question": "July",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaL raH gaL daaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผูก",
      "question": "to bind, tie, attach",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมาชิก",
      "question": "member, subscriber",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL maaM chik↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สิน",
      "question": "property, wealth, riches, possessions",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sin↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เล่ม",
      "question": "(of a book) a volume",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lem↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ความ",
      "question": "(a prefix which converts an adjective or verb into a noun)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แบบ",
      "question": "plan, kind, design, pattern, style, model, type, (formal term officially endorsed by the Royal Institute) version (of software)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baaep↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สิงโต",
      "question": "lion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[singR dto:h→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พ้น",
      "question": "in the clear, safe from",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เฉพาะ",
      "question": "(is) specific, particular, limited, provisional",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL phaw↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คูณ",
      "question": "to multiply, mathematical multiplication, \"times\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuun→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มัก",
      "question": "often, frequently, inclined towards, prone towards",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นำ",
      "question": "to lead or precede",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผิด",
      "question": "(is) incorrect, wrong, mistaken, false, faulty, guilty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ป้องกัน",
      "question": "to defend, protect against, prevent, prevent against, bar",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaawngF gan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วาง",
      "question": "to lay down, to put down, to put on (airs), to deposit, to place, to set down",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรียบร้อย",
      "question": "(is) polite and well mannered",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiapF raawy↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แก",
      "question": "(impolite or colloquial usage) he, him, she, her, they, them, you",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaae→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลด",
      "question": "to decrease, reduce, lower, diminish, lessen",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[loht↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไส",
      "question": "to push forward, to shove, to thrust",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เจริญ",
      "question": "(is) prosperous",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaL reern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทา",
      "question": "to apply, paint, put on lotion or makeup",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรมเนียม",
      "question": "custom, customs, tradition, traditional usage",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thamM niiam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขึ้น",
      "question": "to ascend, raise, rise, go up",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheun↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชายหาด",
      "question": "beach",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaaiM haat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุตรี",
      "question": "daughter",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bootL ree→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรม",
      "question": "virtue, morality, precept, scruples, rightneousness, principles, doctrine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครอง",
      "question": "to rule, to govern, to regulate by authority, to exercise or assert authority, to direct",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แนะนำ",
      "question": "(of an idea) to introduce, suggest, advise, direct, guide, recommend",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naeH nam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แพ้",
      "question": "allergic to, have an allergy to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชัก",
      "question": "to pull at, to discount, draw, take away, withdraw, to pull upon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บำรุง",
      "question": "to care for, maintain, nurture, support",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bamM roong→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราย",
      "question": "list of items, record, tally, story, account, item, statement, case",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลอง",
      "question": "to try, test, to experiment with, to try out",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กะ",
      "question": "to estimate or guess, to reckon, plan or plot",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ga↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยิ่ง",
      "question": "excessively, extremely, very much, even more so",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขนาด",
      "question": "dimensions, size, measurement",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaL naat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชิง",
      "question": "to snatch away, to wrest away from, to contest or compete for, to vie",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ching→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมุน",
      "question": "to dial, turn, revolve, spin, rotate, whirl",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[moon↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น้อง",
      "question": "younger sibling, younger friend, younger colleague",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลำดับ",
      "question": "sequence, order, line, arrangement, series",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lamM dap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขด",
      "question": "to roll into a coil, to coil, to bend, to twist",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทาย",
      "question": "(of a problem) to solve, to answer",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรม",
      "question": "dharma, religious teaching, religious duty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลิ้น",
      "question": "tongue",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lin↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขด",
      "question": "coil, ring, circle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กล่าว",
      "question": "to speak, say, utter, tell or relate, to address, mention, declare",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กุมาร",
      "question": "infant, child, boy, young lad, son, prince",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gooL maan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝา",
      "question": "lid or cover of a pot or bowl, cap",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตะเกียง",
      "question": "lamp, oil lamp, lantern",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL giiang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครอง",
      "question": "to occupy, to possess and enjoy the use of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไถ",
      "question": "to plow, thrust, push, to clip hair very short",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลัก",
      "question": "post, pillar, pole, stake, lingam",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิเศษ",
      "question": "(is) special, particular, unique, extraordinary, extra",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH saeht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พาย",
      "question": "to row, to paddle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ค่ะ",
      "question": "(word added by a female speaker to the end of every statement to convey politeness)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kha↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กุมภาพันธ์",
      "question": "February",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[goomM phaaM phan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทั้ง",
      "question": "all, entire, whole, wholly, both (...and), while",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thang↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กฎหมาย",
      "question": "law",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gohtL maai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลี้ยง",
      "question": "to have a banquet, to hold a party or feast",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[liiang↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชาว",
      "question": "folk, people, people of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โยน",
      "question": "to throw, pitch, cast, fling, hurl",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yo:hn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จำเป็น",
      "question": "(is) necessary, essential, required, to need to (do something)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jamM bpen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "to bargain or haggle, to negotiate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โอ",
      "question": "pomelo citrus maxima",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[o:h→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แผน",
      "question": "plan, pattern, scheme, project, model",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaen↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทีเดียว",
      "question": "quite, very",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[theeM diaao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชนะ",
      "question": "to conquer, defeat, beat, win",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaH na↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมวก",
      "question": "hat, cap",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บัญชา",
      "question": "to command, direct",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[banM chaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เจ็ด",
      "question": "seven, the number or quantity seven",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช่าง",
      "question": "engineer, artisan, mechanic, craftsman, specialist, repairman, barber",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครบ",
      "question": "(is) complete, whole, every, entire, due",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrohp↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แยก",
      "question": "intersection",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaaek↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นึก",
      "question": "to suppose, think or conjecture, to feel, ponder, harbor a feeling or doubt,",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neuk↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลม",
      "question": "(is) circular, round",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กล้า",
      "question": "brave, fearless, courageous",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มกราคม",
      "question": "January",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mohkH gaL raaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ที่",
      "question": "at, on the site of, within, amidst, in the location of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thee↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันเสาร์",
      "question": "Saturday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM sao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คับ",
      "question": "(is) tight, confined, crowded, closely packed, tight-fitting, close-fitting",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทดลอง",
      "question": "to experiment, test",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thohtH laawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราว",
      "question": "handrail, railing, rod, rack",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raao→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สิงหาคม",
      "question": "August",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[singR haaR khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เคือง",
      "question": "(is) angry, peeved, indignant, wrathful, irate, offended, annoyed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheuuang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร่วม",
      "question": "to share, join, partake, participate, unite, affiliate with, associate with, team with",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruaam↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลบ",
      "question": "to erase",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohp↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซ้ำ",
      "question": "(is) repeated, recurrent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sam↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยก",
      "question": "to raise, to hoist (up), to revoke, to advance, to abolish, to elevate, to lift, to erect",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yohk↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกียจคร้าน",
      "question": "(is) lazy, indolent, idle, slothful, inert, inactive",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giiatL khraan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทั้งหลาย",
      "question": "all, many, several",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thangH laai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาศัย",
      "question": "to inhabit, live in, or dwell in a place, to reside",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM sai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อันตราย",
      "question": "(is) dangerous, harmful, evil",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[anM dtaL raai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรือน",
      "question": "household, dwelling, abode, (typically a) wooden house",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuuan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสียง",
      "question": "tone, sound, volume, noise",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[siiang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จดหมาย",
      "question": "postal letter, mail, a letter",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johtL maai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทองคำ",
      "question": "gold, gold nugget",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawngM kham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สลึง",
      "question": "salueng, 25 sadang, ¼ of 1 baht",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL leung↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภายนอก",
      "question": "(is) outside, external",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM naawk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาค",
      "question": "section, portion, part (I, II, III, etc., of a movie or novel), region, division, side, segment, share, period, time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมเด็จ",
      "question": "abbot, great one, a title of high rank for a queen and highly revered Buddhist priests",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR det↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพียง",
      "question": "only, merely, up until the point, as much as, as far as, till, just until",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiiang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พ้อง",
      "question": "(is) synonymous, alike-sounding, identical, in agreement, coincident, simultaneous, allied",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaawng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โอกาส",
      "question": "chance, opportunity, occasion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[o:hM gaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทรง",
      "question": "(royal use only) (prefix which transforms common verbs (and sometimes nouns) into the verbs (and nouns) for royal language showing actions of mounting (a horse) or holding (an object), etc. The meanings will depend on such ensuing verbs.)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สังเกต",
      "question": "to notice, to observe, to perceive, to recconoiter, to make a note of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sangR gaeht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แปลง",
      "question": "plot of land, flower bed, field",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พฤหัสบดี",
      "question": "(formal, general) Jupiter",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phreuH hatL saL baawM dee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มัธยม",
      "question": "secondary education, high school",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[matH thaH yohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จัด",
      "question": "strong, intense, excessive, severe (especially when speaking of the weather)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เจ้า",
      "question": "prince, princess, ruler, esteemed person, lord, master, holy being",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใคร",
      "question": "anyone, anybody, someone, somebody, whoever",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เจริญ",
      "question": "to progress, grow, prosper, thrive, expand",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaL reern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แสวง",
      "question": "to pursue, seek, look for, search out",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL waaeng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทน",
      "question": "to bear, stand, put up with, tolerate, endure, last",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ค่ำ",
      "question": "evening, dusk, sunset time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิเศษ",
      "question": "distinction, uniqueness, peculiarity, oddity",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH saeht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เข้า",
      "question": "to enter, go in, to penetrate, to insert, to approach",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสื่อม",
      "question": "to deteriorate, to depreciate, decrease, decline",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuuam↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิธี",
      "question": "ceremony, event",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH thee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แนะนำ",
      "question": "(of a person) to introduce",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naeH nam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสีย",
      "question": "(is) spent, broken, wasted, malfunctioning, defective, out of order, rotten, bad",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[siia↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หก",
      "question": "six, the number or quantity six",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แก้",
      "question": "to undo, remedy, mend, repair, cure, correct, counteract, rectify, quench, slake, relieve, edit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaae↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จีน",
      "question": "China, Chinese",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jeen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขีด",
      "question": "a scratch",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แจ่ม",
      "question": "clear, bright, distinct, cheerful",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaem↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "connector",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระทำ",
      "question": "to do, make, perform, carry out, act",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยอด",
      "question": "top, pinnacle, tip, peak, summit, crown, zenith",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawt↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชลประทาน",
      "question": "irrigation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohnM laH bpraL thaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลุก",
      "question": "to rise, stand up, get up, arise",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[look↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลือก",
      "question": "to select or choose, elect, pick",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โบราณ",
      "question": "(is) ancient",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bo:hM raan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ว่า",
      "question": "to speak, say, aver, think",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สถานี",
      "question": "station",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL thaaR nee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รักษา",
      "question": "to remedy, treat, or cure an illness",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rakH saa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บัง",
      "question": "to hide, to conceal, to block the view, to screen, share or shield, to obscure",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วาจา",
      "question": "speech, words, utterance, remarks, statements",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waaM jaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอบ",
      "question": "cycle, round, circuit, trip, anniversary, revolution",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawp↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หน้า",
      "question": "face, front, facade, visage, (to nod) head",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หน้าที่",
      "question": "duty, function, obligation, responsibility",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaF thee↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ด้าน",
      "question": "(is) callous, hard, hard-hearted, hardened, shameless",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สติ",
      "question": "mindfulness, consciousness, mind, thought, sense, sensibility, sense of responsiveness, attention, attentiveness, reflection, balance",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL dti↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ริม",
      "question": "by, beside, alongside, at the side of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rim→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อนุญาต",
      "question": "to give permission or license, permit, allow, grant, consent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aL nooH yaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกือบ",
      "question": "almost, nearly, close to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[geuuap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลาก",
      "question": "to drag, pull at, haul",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พื้น",
      "question": "ground, land, foundation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuun↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เปลือก",
      "question": "bark, rind, husk, shell, skin, peel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpleuuak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เบอร์",
      "question": "number, digit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[buuhr→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วิธี",
      "question": "method, way, mode of operation, procedure",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wiH thee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทิ้ง",
      "question": "to abandon, discard, throw away, to leave (an object) behind",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thing↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทั้งปวง",
      "question": "all, in total, completely, of every kind, as a whole",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thangH bpuaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จัด",
      "question": "to adjust, arrange, fix",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "งาม",
      "question": "(is) beautiful, pretty, attractive, gorgeous, fine, complete",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แจ้ง",
      "question": "to notify, advise, inform, make apparent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaaeng↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สัก",
      "question": "to tattoo",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลับ",
      "question": "to shut, sleep, to be asleep, go to bed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตาม",
      "question": "to fetch (someone), to send for (someone)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกี่ยว",
      "question": "to hitch, to link, to hook up",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราก",
      "question": "root, foundation, source",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ด้าน",
      "question": "side, face, direction, quarter, sector, aspect, surface, field, viewpoint",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แบ่ง",
      "question": "to share, divide into parts, apportion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baeng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สินค้า",
      "question": "merchandise, product, finished good",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sinR khaa↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สวัสดีครับ",
      "question": "(spoken politely by a male) hello, goodbye",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL watL deeM khrap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปฏิบัติ",
      "question": "to execute, perform, do, act, behave, practice",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaL dtiL bat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เส้น",
      "question": "geometric line, string, filament, thread, rope, cord, route or routing, ply",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เบี้ย",
      "question": "a counter used in gambling",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[biia↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แล",
      "question": "to look at, to watch, to see, to glance, to take a look",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laae→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คน",
      "question": "person, guy, people, man, human being",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ค้า",
      "question": "to trade, to do business, to do commerce, to barter, to buy and sell, to vend, to traffic in",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กำไร",
      "question": "profit, gain",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM rai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พระยา",
      "question": "(title of ancient Thai civil nobility nobility between พระ  (Phra) and เจ้าพระยา  (Chao Phraya))",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraH yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชัด",
      "question": "(is) sharp, clear, focused, concise",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chat↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สำเร็จ",
      "question": "to succeed, finish, complete, accomplish",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR ret↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกรง",
      "question": "(is) afraid, fearful, inspired with awe, respectful of, fearful, filled with reverence",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graehng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัด",
      "question": "to go against, to stop, to hinder, to oppose, to obstruct, to block",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สวม",
      "question": "to wear, to put on, to dress with, to cover, to clothe",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suaam↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพียน",
      "question": "to add to, to augment, to supplement",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiian→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฟัก",
      "question": "gourd, squash Cucurbita",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลาย",
      "question": "several, numerous, a variety, many, sundry, diverse, (the prefix) \"multi-\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไข",
      "question": "to wind (up) or unwind, to turn",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อย่าง",
      "question": "variety, style, pattern, type, kind, sort, mode, manner, method",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไข",
      "question": "animal fat, lard, tallow, (of human bones) marrow",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สรรเสริญ",
      "question": "to praise, admire, laud",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sanR seern↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กาย",
      "question": "body, human body, physique",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฟ้า",
      "question": "the sky, firmament, heaven",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faa↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แมลง",
      "question": "bug, insect",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maH laaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดัง",
      "question": "(is) loud, noisy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คือ",
      "question": "(copula) to be, (conjunction used for equivalence definitions)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheuu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซ้ำ",
      "question": "to repeat, to recur, to reiterate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sam↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทรง",
      "question": "form, figure, style",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาย",
      "question": "(referring to placement in space or time) location",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่ำ",
      "question": "(is) low, short, depressed, base",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกี่ยวข้อง",
      "question": "(is) involved, concerned",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaaoL khaawng↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สวน",
      "question": "garden, field, park, farm, plantation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suaan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พล",
      "question": "general, General (military rank)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ห่ม",
      "question": "cover, close",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohm↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดำเนิน",
      "question": "to implement, to go forward with a plan, to conduct or proceed, to operate, carry out",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[damM neern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แผ่นดิน",
      "question": "land, country, kingdom, ground, earth, plot of land",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaenL din→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตุลาคม",
      "question": "October",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtooL laaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผิว",
      "question": "skin, complexion, surface",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท้อง",
      "question": "belly, abdomen, stomach",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บทบรรณาธิการ",
      "question": "editorial",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bohtL banM naaM thiH gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แน่น",
      "question": "(is) crowded, busy (restaurant, etc), tightly packed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ส่อง",
      "question": "to look at with a telescope, microscope, or binoculars",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แผ่น",
      "question": "sheet, tablet, plank, strip, piece",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaen↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตลอด",
      "question": "during, all during, throughout, through, in (e.g., in over 20 years)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL laawt↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คู",
      "question": "ditch, moat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกี่ยว",
      "question": "to mow or harvest, reap, cut",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระงับ",
      "question": "to halt, to curb, to stop, cease, mitigate, check suppress, repress",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH ngap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลาง",
      "question": "the middle, the center",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัง",
      "question": "to confine, coop up, imprison, retain, detain, cage, incarcerate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนัก",
      "question": "(of a medical condition or other problem) (is) serious",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พลเมือง",
      "question": "a citizen, an inhabitant, people, population",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohnM laH meuuang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้น",
      "question": "(a prefix used for plant or tree names) plant, stalk, trunk, tree",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtohn↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โกร่ง",
      "question": "apothecary's mortar",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gro:hng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตัดสิน",
      "question": "to decide, judge, referee",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtatL sin↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โลก",
      "question": "the planet Earth",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lo:hk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปั้น",
      "question": "to mold, form, fabricate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลบ",
      "question": "mathematical subtraction, minus",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohp↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นัก",
      "question": "(word used before a verb or noun to describe a profession) person who, enthusiast, devotee, expert",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กรม",
      "question": "(of government) a department",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[grohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครั้ง",
      "question": "(frequency) time, occasion, instance, event, occurrence",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrang↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอง",
      "question": "(of ranking and order) deputy, vice-, subordinate, associate, secondary, (competition, status of wife) second, next",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กร",
      "question": "worker, laborer, doer, workman, (a suffix indicating) a person who... (does certain things), or an object that... (performs a certain function)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พยาน",
      "question": "witness",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaH yaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภรรยา",
      "question": "wife",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phanM raH yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สนาม",
      "question": "field, park, lawn, playground, meadow, yard, turf, grassy field",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL naam↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดง",
      "question": "jungle, thick grove",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จังหวัด",
      "question": "province, of which Thailand has 76",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jangM wat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไร",
      "question": "(suffix indicating qualification, quantification, or interrogation, as indicated below)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บาท",
      "question": "Thai currency: Baht (TH฿)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถอย",
      "question": "to withdraw, move back, retreat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawy↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กาชาด",
      "question": "a red cross",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaM chaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลี้ยว",
      "question": "to turn, make a change in direction",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[liaao↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมมุติ",
      "question": "to assume, suppose",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR moot↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พร้อม",
      "question": "(is) ready, set, finished, complete",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraawm↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สัก",
      "question": "(general) (is) teak",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หม้อ",
      "question": "a pot for cooking",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กษัตริย์",
      "question": "(general) king",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaL sat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สงสัย",
      "question": "to doubt, suspect, wonder about",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR sai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สระ",
      "question": "a vowel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL ra↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เก็บ",
      "question": "to collect, preserve, keep, fetch",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gep↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดับ",
      "question": "to eliminate, to stop, to die or pass away",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธันวาคม",
      "question": "December",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thanM waaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โกรธ",
      "question": "(is) mad, angry, pissed off",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gro:ht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลำพัง",
      "question": "individual, private, personal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lamM phang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชำนาญ",
      "question": "(is) experienced, skilled, expert, adroit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chamM naan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สืบ",
      "question": "to succeed, to pass on to another, to continue, to advance",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuup↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ง่าย",
      "question": "(is) easy, not difficult, simple",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซีก",
      "question": "section, piece, part, portion (as in the English prefix) hemi-",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seek↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใต้",
      "question": "South, Southern",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลื่อน",
      "question": "to postpone",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สม",
      "question": "(is) becoming, suitable for, appropriate, conforming, worthy of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohm↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นับถือ",
      "question": "to respect, esteem, revere, reckon, hold in high regard, believe in, profess",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[napH theuu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสมอ",
      "question": "(is) even, level, flush",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL muuhr↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พัก",
      "question": "to halt, lay-over, stop for the night, stay overnight at a place, to rest or relax, remain at a place temporarily",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พลอย",
      "question": "gem, gems, gemstones, jewels, jewelry",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phlaawy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บริษัท",
      "question": "company, firm, corporation, congregration, audience, meeting, assembly",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawM riH sat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โง่",
      "question": "(is) stupid, silly, dumb, foolish, vain",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngo:h↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทวีป",
      "question": "continent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH weep↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บรรดา",
      "question": "all, in general, those",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[banM daa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บาง",
      "question": "(is) scarce, limited, few, rare, thin",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กา",
      "question": "teapot-kettle with a spout, tick, sign or mark set against an item",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมบัติ",
      "question": "assets, treasure, fortune, riches, wealth",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR bat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร่าง",
      "question": "shape, figure, body, outline, form",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เขียน",
      "question": "to write, to draw",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khiian↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กา",
      "question": "to make a check-mark, X or cross marks",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สิบ",
      "question": "ten, the number or quantity ten",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sip↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เช่น",
      "question": "as",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เคียง",
      "question": "(is) adjoining, connected, beside, near, close together",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khiiang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เท",
      "question": "to take away in large numbers, to haul off, to pour",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaeh→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทรง",
      "question": "hair style, hairdo",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รูป",
      "question": "shape, form, contour, appearance, similarity-to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruup↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ครั้น",
      "question": "when (something occurs), if (something happened)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khran↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ญี่ปุ่น",
      "question": "Japan",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yeeF bpoon↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เทวดา",
      "question": "a male angel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaehM waH daa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สะพาน",
      "question": "bridge, pier",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL phaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สามี",
      "question": "husband",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saaR mee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระยะ",
      "question": "a space, interval or separation (as in punctuation), a period, a stage, distance, time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH ya↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชั้น",
      "question": "class, rank, grade",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันศุกร์",
      "question": "Friday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM sook↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เท็จ",
      "question": "(is) false, untrue, dishonest, deceptive, spurious",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thet↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พึ่ง",
      "question": "just now, a moment ago, recently",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheung↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "(of contracts, ropes, etc.) to extend, to lengthen, (of phone calls) to connect, (of words) to join, to link, (of knowledge) to receive or inherit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสนาบดี",
      "question": "secretary of state, minister, commander in chief",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saehR naaM baawM dee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ติด",
      "question": "(of a person) to become (figuratively) fixated (on something), to think about (something) to an extreme and excessive degree, to be (figuratively) absorbed, to be obsessed (with someone or something), to be crazy or mad about, to be fascinated by",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สถาน",
      "question": "place, site, location, locality",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL thaan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อวด",
      "question": "to boast, brag, show off, display, flaunt",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[uaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สามารถ",
      "question": "(is) capable, able",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saaR maat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แข่ง",
      "question": "to compete, to race, to contend with, to strive for, to vie",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaeng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทุกข์",
      "question": "suffering, sorrow, distress, adversity, trouble, anxiety, first of the Four Noble Truths",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thook↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ญาติ",
      "question": "relative, kin, relations, cousins",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สำนัก",
      "question": "office, bureau, institute, institution",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR nak↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร่ม",
      "question": "umbrella, parasol",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rohm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระจาย",
      "question": "to disperse, distribute, broadcast, spread, scatter",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL jaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รู",
      "question": "tiny hole, cavity, gap",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruu→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกิน",
      "question": "to exceed, go beyond, overreach, surpass",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[geern→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตำ",
      "question": "beat, pound an object, pulverize",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนุ่ม",
      "question": "teenage male, young man, adolescent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[noom↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ค้น",
      "question": "to search",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khohn↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มั่งมี",
      "question": "(is) rich, wealthy, affluent, opulent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mangF mee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อักษร",
      "question": "alphabet, (of the alphabet:) letter, character, glyph, word, sound, vowels, consonants",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[akL saawn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บริสุทธิ์",
      "question": "(is) innocent, pure, uncontaminated, virgin, fine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawM riH soot↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไปรษณีย์",
      "question": "post, mail, post office, postal system",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraiM saL nee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นับ",
      "question": "to count",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝ่าย",
      "question": "side, party, faction, group",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นอก",
      "question": "(is) outside of, external to, foreign, alien",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสียใจ",
      "question": "(is) very sorry, grieving",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[siiaR jai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปล่อย",
      "question": "to let go, relinquish, discharge, emit, abandon, release, ease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaawy↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประชุม",
      "question": "to assemble, have a meeting",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL choom→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สวรรค์",
      "question": "heaven, paradise",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL wan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นุ่ง",
      "question": "to dress, don, put on, wear clothing, to get dressed, attire, clothe, garb, robe, slip on or into",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[noong↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ละเอียด",
      "question": "(is) detailed, exact, delicate, fine, powdered, finely powdered, meticulous, careful, thorough, methodical",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH iiat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าม",
      "question": "to cross over, pass over, step over",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaam↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บท",
      "question": "chapter of a book, lesson of a schoolbook, article in a magazine, verse, stanza",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดี๋ยวนี้",
      "question": "now, nowadays, \"Right now!\", \"Pronto!\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaaoR nee↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช่วย",
      "question": "to help, to aid, to assist, to contribute, to please",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuay↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บ่าย",
      "question": "afternoon hours between 1:00 p.m. and 4:00 p.m.",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาด",
      "question": "to tear, rip or become torn or ripped asunder, to separate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภูมิ",
      "question": "(is) grand, proud, dignified",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM mi↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แสง",
      "question": "light, ray, light ray, beam of light",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saaeng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โปรด",
      "question": "(a formal word of request) \"please\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpro:ht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมี",
      "question": "bear (the animal)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mee↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เถิด",
      "question": "(a formal word placed after a verb or a sentence to mark or indicate an exhortation, a command or an entreaty) let's, let us, let's go for it, let's do it",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[theert↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝึก",
      "question": "to drill, to train, to practice, to exercise, to teach",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[feuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธาตุ",
      "question": "one of the four ancient elements: earth, water, air, or fire",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใส",
      "question": "(is) clear, transparent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประพฤติ",
      "question": "manner, conduct, deportment, behavior",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL phreut↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บิดา",
      "question": "father",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[biL daa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ล้วน",
      "question": "(is) pure, absolute, pristine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิจารณา",
      "question": "to consider, to appraise, to study, to examine, to investigate, to reckon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH jaaM raH naa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระดาน",
      "question": "game board",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มัน",
      "question": "oil, fat, grease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[man→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกี่ยว",
      "question": "to concern",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พฤษภาคม",
      "question": "May",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phreutH saL phaaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เล่น",
      "question": "to play, have fun, enjoy, amuse, jest, have fun on the Internet",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[len↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมตตา",
      "question": "(Buddhism) goodwill, kindness, mercy, clemency, compassion, kindheartedness",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maehtF dtaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปราบปราม",
      "question": "to repress, quell, quash, subjugate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraapL bpraam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ค่อย",
      "question": "gently, softly, little by little, gradually, cautiously",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawy↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สัญญา",
      "question": "legal contract, promise, agreement, treaty, pact, deal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sanR yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เทียม",
      "question": "(is) artificial, false, imitation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราชา",
      "question": "royal, of or pertaining to king",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaM chaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฟ้อง",
      "question": "to sue",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faawng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดี๋ยว",
      "question": "soon, shortly, momentarily",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มณฑล",
      "question": "precinct, administrative region",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mohnM thohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนา",
      "question": "(is) thick, (of fabric) heavy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไม้",
      "question": "wood, woods, forest, stick, rod",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มนุษย์",
      "question": "human being, man, human, homo sapiens",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maH noot↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประกาศ",
      "question": "bill",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กิจ",
      "question": "errand, duty, work, routine, affair, business",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[git↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กัน",
      "question": "together with",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉะนี้",
      "question": "consequently, so, thus",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL nee↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แย่ง",
      "question": "to catch, to seize, to scramble for, contend for, compete for, wrest",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaaeng↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สำหรับ",
      "question": "for, as for, in order to, for the purpose of, in order that",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR rap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สาว",
      "question": "young woman, girl, unmarried woman, maiden, damsel, lass, lassie (informal), maid, virgin, wench",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระดาน",
      "question": "board, plank, deal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชนวน",
      "question": "fuse, primer, harbinger",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaH nuaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสือ",
      "question": "tiger",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuua↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาษิต",
      "question": "saying, proverb, motto, saw, teaching, maxim, adage",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM sit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แมว",
      "question": "cat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaeo→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จับ",
      "question": "to arrest, catch, get a hold of, touch, capture, seize",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดิน",
      "question": "dirt, earth, soil, ground, land, kingdom, realm",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[din→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เข้าหู",
      "question": "to hear, to have heard",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaoF huu↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้อ",
      "question": "joint, point of intersection, articulation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมอก",
      "question": "fog, mist, foggy, misty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กำหนด",
      "question": "to schedule, set, limit, appoint, settle, condition, agree upon, assign, specify, define, establish",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM noht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชัวร์",
      "question": "(Thai transcription of the foreign loanword) sure, surely, certainly",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เดือด",
      "question": "to boil by heat, to be iritated, to be provoked, to boil over, to be furious, to be in a rage",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deuuat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เทียบ",
      "question": "to compare, to place alongside, to escort",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiap↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จ้าง",
      "question": "to hire, engage, employ",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตะวัน",
      "question": "the Sun",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL wan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กำลัง",
      "question": "(auxiliary verb indicating the present participle, meaning \"in the act of\" or \"in the process of\", similar to the English suffix, \"-ing\")",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM lang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตัด",
      "question": "to cut, mow, trim, sever, hew, make (a suit), build (a road)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรียบร้อย",
      "question": "(is) neat, ready, all set, all in order, orderly, tidy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiapF raawy↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คลาย",
      "question": "to diminish, to unwind, to relax, to slacken, to abate, to lessen, to untwist, to unfurl, to decrease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khlaai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท้าย",
      "question": "at the back, at the end",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปัญญา",
      "question": "(Buddhism) intelligence, wisdom, sharpness, wit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpanM yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตรัส",
      "question": "(as a king or royalty) to say, remark, speak, declare, pronounce",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtrat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คดี",
      "question": "lawsuit, legal action, case",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaH dee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ห่ม",
      "question": "to cover, clothe, wrap, enclose, dress",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohm↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เตือน",
      "question": "to caution, warn, remind",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dteuuan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดำริ",
      "question": "(Royal use only) to think",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[damM ri↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จำพวก",
      "question": "species, type, group",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jamM phuaak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาด",
      "question": "(is) in short supply, not on hand, lacking, needing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลัก",
      "question": "basis, foundation, principle, maxim, doctrine, tenet",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัน",
      "question": "a bowl or basin used for dipping water",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภายใน",
      "question": "within, by (a certain time frame)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM nai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เหลน",
      "question": "great-grandchild",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laehn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพียงไร",
      "question": "how many",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiiangM rai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มนตรี",
      "question": "a high government official or adviser, a mandarin",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mohnM dtree→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จำ",
      "question": "to remember, recall, memorize, retain, recognize, recollect",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เปลือง",
      "question": "to use up, consume, waste",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpleuuang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ล่วง",
      "question": "to exceed, overstep, pass, to go beyond",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดับ",
      "question": "to extinguish, put out, vanquish, dead",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สมัย",
      "question": "era, times, period, age",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL mai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใคร่",
      "question": "to desire, wish, prefer",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กรรม",
      "question": "deed, kamma, karma, sin, bad karma earned",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อเมริกา",
      "question": "America, United States, American",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aL maehM riH gaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกี่ยว",
      "question": "(is) entangled with, (is) hugging, (is) embracing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อธิบาย",
      "question": "to explain, define, describe",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aL thiH baai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาณาเขต",
      "question": "territory",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM naaM khaeht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรมดา",
      "question": "(is) usual, ordinary, normal, average, plain, regular, natural, common",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thamM maH daa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสื้อ",
      "question": "shirt, blouse, jacket",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuua↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทับ",
      "question": "to place on top of or overlay, superimpose, run over",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มากมาย",
      "question": "very much, plentiful, much, many, countless, various, several, a lot of, many, diversified, miscellaneous, numerous",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maakF maai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บุรุษ",
      "question": "man, male, gentleman, person, people, mankind, humans",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[booL root↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตู้",
      "question": "storage cabinet, post office box, cupboard, locker for luggage, (gym clothing) locker",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtuu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตรง",
      "question": "(is) straight, direct, exactly, upright, vertical",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtrohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขา",
      "question": "(of a person) party, side, sort, type",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หมาย",
      "question": "warrant, notice, order, point, writ, summons, decree",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉบับ",
      "question": "edition, copy, issue of a magazine or newspaper, (formal term officially endorsed by the Royal Institute) version (of software)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL bap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไต่",
      "question": "to climb, to scale (a mountain), to move up slowly and carefully",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtai↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระหว่าง",
      "question": "between, in the middle of, the middle, among",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH waang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลีก",
      "question": "to avoid, evade, dodge, get out of the way",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leek↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภายหลัง",
      "question": "afterward, later, afterwards",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM lang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฟ้อง",
      "question": "to accuse, prosecute",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faawng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เปลี่ยน",
      "question": "to change, replace, to convert, to alter, swap, substitute, to transplant",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpliian↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาบน้ำ",
      "question": "to bathe, take a bath, take a shower, swim",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aapL naam↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เผย",
      "question": "to open, to disclose, to discover, to unveil, to uncover, to reveal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheeuy↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไหม้",
      "question": "to burn",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ละออง",
      "question": "dust, spray, mist, particles, fine particles, powder, fall-out",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH aawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภัย",
      "question": "harm, danger, catastrophe, fear, dread, peril",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อำนาจ",
      "question": "authority, power",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[amM naat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โจทย์",
      "question": "accusation, objection",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jo:ht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นิทาน",
      "question": "fable, story, yarn, tale, folklore, fairytale",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[niH thaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท่าน",
      "question": "(a respectful 2nd or 3rd person singular pronoun) you, he, she, him, her",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[than↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สุข",
      "question": "happiness, content, bliss, pleasure",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sook↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จริต",
      "question": "behavior, conduct, act (outward act)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaL rit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เล่า",
      "question": "to relate a story, to tell, to recount, to narrate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท้าย",
      "question": "stern, back, rear end",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตรา",
      "question": "brand name, brand, seal, stamp, mark, hallmark, device, decoration, badge",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtraa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขว้าง",
      "question": "to throw, to pitch, to toss, to hurl, to cast, to fling",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พอ",
      "question": "(is) sufficient, (does) suffice, (is) adequate, enough",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaw→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สตรี",
      "question": "female, woman, lady",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL dtree→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลึก",
      "question": "(is) deep",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuk↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สั่ง",
      "question": "to order merchandise, food, or medicine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไร่",
      "question": "the rai, a unit of land measure",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไข้",
      "question": "fever, a temperature of the body, sickness",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กันยายน",
      "question": "September",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ganM yaaM yohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลง",
      "question": "to come down, go down, get off, get out of, descend, land",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สู้",
      "question": "to face, to be against",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าราชการ",
      "question": "government official, civil servant",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaF raatF chaH gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ศุกร์",
      "question": "(general) Venus",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sook↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โทษ",
      "question": "punishment, penalty, penance, guilt, blame, offence, crime, penalty, ill-effect, harm, danger, fault, defect, sinfulness, misdeed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tho:ht↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภาพ",
      "question": "image, picture, drawing, vision",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaap↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หยด",
      "question": "(of liquid) a drop",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัน",
      "question": "to turn oneself around, to face in a direction",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[han↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมื่อไร",
      "question": "(used in a question) when",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuuaF rai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภูมิ",
      "question": "status, standing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM mi↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระนั้น",
      "question": "in that way, like that",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL nan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้อน",
      "question": "to herd, or corner, gather together",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawn↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สงคราม",
      "question": "war, battle, hostilities, conflict, combat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR khraam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สภา",
      "question": "council, assembly",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL phaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เบื้อง",
      "question": "(prefix for a (spatial) direction)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[beuuang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อัตรา",
      "question": "rate, rating, criteria, established scale, limit, standard, class, grade, standing",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[atL raa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บ้าง",
      "question": "some, any, partially",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยุติธรรม",
      "question": "(is) fair, just",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yootH dtiL tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประเทศ",
      "question": "nation, country",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL thaeht↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ที",
      "question": "turn, outing, chance, opportunity, instance, times, occasion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ภายใน",
      "question": "the inside, the interior",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM nai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สูง",
      "question": "(is) tall, high, advanced",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suung↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อด",
      "question": "to abstain (from food, e.g.), fast, refrain, cease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[oht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คอย",
      "question": "to wait or wait for",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิมพ์",
      "question": "to print, type, importing, make an impression of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phim→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จด",
      "question": "to take note, to jot down",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[joht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทอง",
      "question": "gold, Au",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช่อง",
      "question": "passage, aperature, gap, hole, lane, opening, (euphonious word for บ้าน )",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaawng↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ล้ม",
      "question": "to fall down",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohm↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาจ",
      "question": "(used with another verb to indicate possibility) may, might",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เว้น",
      "question": "to exclude, omit, skip over",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wen↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลิก",
      "question": "separate from another person, to break up a relationship",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leerk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ด้วย",
      "question": "together, along with, also, too, as well, likewise, in addition to doing some other thing (as another action performed by the same subject)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[duay↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตอบ",
      "question": "to answer, reply, respond, in return",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รางวัล",
      "question": "award, prize, reward",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raangM wan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มอง",
      "question": "to look at, to see, to stare at, to glance, to eye",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ละคร",
      "question": "(general) theatrical presentation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH khaawn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถนน",
      "question": "road, boulevard, avenue, street",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaL nohn↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รีบ",
      "question": "to hurry",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reep↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยอด",
      "question": "excellent, superb, perfect, great",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawt↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แผ่",
      "question": "to expand, spread out, diffuse, stretch out, extend, broaden, unfold, unroll",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปัญหา",
      "question": "problem, trouble, difficulty",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpanM haa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เกียรติยศ",
      "question": "honor, prestige, fame, renown, reputation, dignity",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giiatL dtiL yoht↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อุ้ม",
      "question": "to carry, hold (in arms), to cradle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[oom↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เขต",
      "question": "boundary, border, limit, district, territory, zone",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaeht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ล้าน",
      "question": "million, the number one million (1,000,000)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laan↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ละลาย",
      "question": "to dissolve, melt",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH laai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แถว",
      "question": "(of objects) a row, column, file, line, bank, queue",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaeo↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ดวง",
      "question": "orb, spherical object, astrological sign, stars",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[duaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรม",
      "question": "rule, law, regulation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทิศ",
      "question": "(a named) direction or point of the compass (such as east, west, north, and south, or right and left), a quarter section of the horizon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thit↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ซ่อน",
      "question": "to conceal or hide an item or oneself",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawn↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทรัพย์",
      "question": "asset, wealth, possessions, riches",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บก",
      "question": "land, dry land, terra firma, high ground",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bohk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขยาย",
      "question": "to expand, enlarge, amplify, inflate, magnify",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaL yaai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จัง",
      "question": "greatly, extremely, truly, fully, quite, most, very much so",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สาย",
      "question": "wire, line, rope, string, strap, connection, tie",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "การ",
      "question": "(placed before a verb or noun to create a noun which indicates a general activity, process, or state) the process of..., the activity of..., an enactment of..., the state of... (see notes)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พึง",
      "question": "(written) should, ought, ought to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheung→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แม้",
      "question": "though, if, provided, even, even if",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maae↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรียก",
      "question": "to call out, called, to be named",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระมัง",
      "question": "likely as not, perhaps, maybe, probably",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL mang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไร้",
      "question": "(is) without, lacking, devoid of, in need of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เก้า",
      "question": "nine, the number or quantity nine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรม",
      "question": "justice, fairness",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปราศจาก",
      "question": "(is) without, separate from, (is) rid of, (is) free from",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraatL saL jaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท่อ",
      "question": "ditch",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อ่อน",
      "question": "(is) soft, pliable, tender",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aawn↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยิง",
      "question": "to fire or shoot (a gun)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาด",
      "question": "to miss or be absent from an event",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มั่นคง",
      "question": "(is) secure, stable, firm, solid, sturdy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[manF khohng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พุธ",
      "question": "(general) Mercury",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phoot↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ล่าง",
      "question": "below, under, down below, underneath",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พล",
      "question": "low member of military or police force",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต่อ",
      "question": "(specifiying temporal sequence) next, afterward, later on, continued",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เช่น",
      "question": "example, sample, specimen",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประโยชน์",
      "question": "benefit, use, usefulness",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL yo:ht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สงสัย",
      "question": "(is) suspicious",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR sai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กรุง",
      "question": "city, town, capital city",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[groong→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประเสริฐ",
      "question": "(is) excellent, glorious, sublime, superb, outstanding",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL seert↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อำเภอ",
      "question": "district, a subdivision of a Thai province",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[amM phuuhr→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันจันทร์",
      "question": "Monday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM jan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แปลง",
      "question": "to convert, modify, adapt",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaaeng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แขก",
      "question": "visitor, guest, foreigner",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaek↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลี้ยง",
      "question": "to feed, nourish, nurture, raise a child or animal, provide for, rear, bring up, foster, nurse",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[liiang↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าพเจ้า",
      "question": "(a first person pronoun) I, me, my (used when writing or speaking formally)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaF phaH jao↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัด",
      "question": "to polish, scrub, rub, abrade, burnish",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พาหนะ",
      "question": "vehicle, carrier, transport",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM haL na↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ข้าง",
      "question": "towards, in the direction of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ห้า",
      "question": "five, the number or quantity five",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร่ม",
      "question": "shade, sunshade, screen, blind, canopy, cover, covering, curtain, shield, veil",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rohm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ธรรม",
      "question": "morals and ethics, the good and decent principles of life",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เชื่อ",
      "question": "to believe, to trust, to have faith in, to rely on",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuua↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โดย",
      "question": "by, via, the method, route, way or mode of attainment",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dooy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หยาบ",
      "question": "(is) crude, coarse, rough, rugged",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลาน",
      "question": "grandchild",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พล",
      "question": "power, force, strength, violence, military force",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พรวน",
      "question": "to break up into pieces, to loosen",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phruaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แรก",
      "question": "(is) first, primary, initial",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaek↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จิต",
      "question": "the mind, mentality",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เถียง",
      "question": "to contradict, to argue, to dispute, to talk back",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพาะ",
      "question": "to culture (germs), to cultivate, to plant, to build (body)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaw↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ย่อม",
      "question": "can, naturally, as a matter of course, inevitably",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลอย",
      "question": "to float, to set afloat or adrift, to waft through (the air)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laawy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สม",
      "question": "to deserve, to meet with",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohm↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประการ",
      "question": "type, kind, sort, species, variety, method, item",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เอง",
      "question": "by oneself, on one's own, personally, myself, oneself, himself, themselves",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aehng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รอง",
      "question": "to collect (liquid) under (a spout)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ก้อน",
      "question": "lump, chunk, small rock, clump, ball, mass",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawn↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชั่ว",
      "question": "(is) bad, evil, wicked",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กู้",
      "question": "to borrow (i.e. money) on interest",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[guu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หาง",
      "question": "tail",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไฉน",
      "question": "why, wherefore",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL nai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เปิด",
      "question": "to open, to turn on, engage",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpeert↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เริ่ม",
      "question": "to begin, to start, commence",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reerm↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มุ่งหมาย",
      "question": "to aim at or for, to intend, to mean, to endeavor, to attempt",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[moongF maai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บาน",
      "question": "to bloom, open, blossom, unfold",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลย",
      "question": "(used for emphasis at the end of a statement) \"...at all.\" — \"...so much!\" — \"...extremely!, completely, directly, simply, without doing anything else first, right away",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leeuy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แทน",
      "question": "to subsitute, represent, replace",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "มอบ",
      "question": "to assign, entrust, turn over, commit, deliver",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawp↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ห่าง",
      "question": "(is) distant, far from, far away, far apart",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haang↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ราง",
      "question": "groove, conduit, rail, track",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เงียบ",
      "question": "(is) quiet, peaceful, silent",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngiiap↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ก็",
      "question": "also, too, as well, well..., (suggestion) should...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชม",
      "question": "to admire, compliment, praise, commend, extol, flatter, pay tribute to, salute, speak highly of",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาด",
      "question": "to lack, need",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สิ่ง",
      "question": "(general term for) a thing, item",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sing↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ก่อน",
      "question": "before, earlier, time gone by, prior to, in advance of, ahead of time, previously, formerly, initially, beforehand, firstly, now, ago",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawn↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แบน",
      "question": "(is) flat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baaen→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขาด",
      "question": "(is) missing a part, incomplete, fragmented",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขา",
      "question": "(a journey or trip) trip, time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เปรียบ",
      "question": "to compare, to contrast",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpriiap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาม",
      "question": "name, designation, appellation",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลักษณะ",
      "question": "characteristic, form, attribute, quality, pattern, style",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lakH saL na↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท่อ",
      "question": "duct, pipe, hose, tube",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaw↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สั้น",
      "question": "(of length) (is) short, squat",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[san↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จิต",
      "question": "of the mind, mental",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jit↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผสม",
      "question": "to combine, mix",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaL sohm↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สร้าง",
      "question": "to build, construct, create, establish, to cause",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประจำ",
      "question": "(is) assigned, permanently placed, constant, fixed",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL jam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เจาะ",
      "question": "to puncture, to bore, to pierce, to punch a hole, to perforate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaw↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสด็จ",
      "question": "(royal use only) to come or go, describing the movement of a Royal person",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL det↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รุ่ง",
      "question": "dawn, daybreak",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[roong↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระเบียบ",
      "question": "order, regulations, system",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH biiap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตาม",
      "question": "to follow, along, around",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ท้าว",
      "question": "(title for a king or god)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaao↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เพลิง",
      "question": "fire, blaze, flame, conflagration",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phleerng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรื่อง",
      "question": "about, relating to, concerning, (as part of the header in an official letter along with เรียน ) \"Subject:\"",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuuang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใด",
      "question": "(is) any",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ร้อง",
      "question": "cry out, to scream, to exclaim, to weep, to sob, to yell, to roar, to squeal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "จบ",
      "question": "to end, to finish",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พร้อม",
      "question": "in unison, concurrently, at the same time, fully",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraawm↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัด",
      "question": "to train, practice, drill or exercise, make proficient, learn to",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เอื้อเฟื้อ",
      "question": "(is) considerate, helpful, generous, friendly",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[euuaF feuua↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เลื่อน",
      "question": "to promote",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuan↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัด",
      "question": "measles, rubseola, a highly contageous skin disease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แต่ง",
      "question": "to adorn, decorate, beautify",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaeng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แล่น",
      "question": "to move, to run, to sail, to glide, to slide, to steam",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laaen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลุม",
      "question": "hole, hole in the ground, pit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[loom↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผ่าน",
      "question": "to cross, pass, pass by, pass through, pass an exam",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaan↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลวง",
      "question": "(is) royal, of the court, superior, official, great",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตน",
      "question": "self, person, man, oneself",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtohn→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บาง",
      "question": "(is) thin, weak, light, fine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รู้",
      "question": "to know a subject or piece of learned information",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruu↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฝาก",
      "question": "to deposit, leave, entrust (something), consign",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นา",
      "question": "rice farm, rice paddy, grain field",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พราหมณ์",
      "question": "Brahman, an ancient religion",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraam→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "คลุม",
      "question": "(is) covered (over), hidden, unclear, enveloped, blanketed (with)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khloom→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เสมียน",
      "question": "clerk, secretary",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL miian↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สหาย",
      "question": "friend, companion, pal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL haai↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เรียง",
      "question": "to arrange, place in order, line up",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "น่า",
      "question": "(a prefix to a verb or adjective to indicate a persistent state or greater intensity of description) extremely, very, intensely, entrenched, really",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขัด",
      "question": "to latch or fasten",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนึ่ง",
      "question": "one, the number or quantity one",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neung↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สตางค์",
      "question": "\"sadang,\" a Thai coin worth one one-hundredth of a Baht, (figuratively meaning) money (in a general sense)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL dtaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไมตรี",
      "question": "amicability, friendship, goodwill, (to be on) good terms",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maiM dtree→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลุง",
      "question": "uncle, elder uncle, elder brother of a parent, great uncle",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[loong→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประกอบ",
      "question": "to combine, to put together, to build, to assemble, to make, to erect",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaawp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แพ้",
      "question": "be defeated (by), to lose (to), to fail",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ยุโรป",
      "question": "(Thai transcription of the foreign loanword) Europe",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yooH ro:hp↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ลิง",
      "question": "monkey",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ling→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พระ",
      "question": "(a title or prefix word used with a most revered person, place, or object) royal",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phra↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทาง",
      "question": "direction, way, path, course, the way",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาหาร",
      "question": "food, meal, diet",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM haan↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แหล่ะ",
      "question": "(a colloquial particle used to emphasize what precedes it)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lae↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หยด",
      "question": "to drip",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "บอก",
      "question": "to say, tell, inform, mention, state, relate, let (someone) know",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แตก",
      "question": "to break, burst, shatter, smash, break in pieces, break out, blossom",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaek↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พวก",
      "question": "(of people, animals) a group, a party",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuaak↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เที่ยง",
      "question": "12:00 h, 12 p.m., noon",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หาก",
      "question": "allowing that, if, despite, rather",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วิทยา",
      "question": "science, knowledge, learning, philosophy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[witH thaH yaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เขียว",
      "question": "(is) green",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khiaao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขีด",
      "question": "draw, scratch, write",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheet↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตระกูล",
      "question": "family, lineage, pedigree, lineage",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtraL guun→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พระ",
      "question": "priest, minister, cleric, monk, padre, god, Buddha image",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phra↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ส่อง",
      "question": "to look in a mirror",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พม่า",
      "question": "Burma, Burmese",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaH maa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทูน",
      "question": "to place in an elevated position, to respect, to revere, to worship, to esteem",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuun→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รู้จัก",
      "question": "(of a person, place, or idea) to know",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruuH jak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "พัน",
      "question": "thousand, the number one thousand (1,000)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เช่น",
      "question": "such as, for example, for instance, like, e.g.",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โรค",
      "question": "disease, sickness, case",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ประพฤติ",
      "question": "to behave, to conduct oneself, to act, to perform or do",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL phreut↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "นิ้ว",
      "question": "finger, toe, digit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[niu↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รัฐบาล",
      "question": "government",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ratH thaL baan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สัตว์",
      "question": "an animal, animals",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทวี",
      "question": "to multiply, increase, add, double",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH wee→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขด",
      "question": "(is) coiled, curled up, rolled up, twisted or bent into a coil",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoht↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปลาบ",
      "question": "(is) thrilling, flashing, shining",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ปมีนาคม",
      "question": "March",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meeM naaM khohm→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉบับ",
      "question": "transcript, document, copy",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL bap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กครอง",
      "question": "to rule, administer, govern",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpohkL khraawng→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กระทรวง",
      "question": "ministry",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL suaang→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เมล็ด",
      "question": "seed, grain, tiny piece, bean",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maH let↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ส่ง",
      "question": "to ship, send or deliver (mail or parcel or package),guayR dtiaaoR emit",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "รับ",
      "question": "to receive, get, accept, catch a thrown object, take, to fetch, to pick (someone) up, (colloq.) telephone call",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rap↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตึก",
      "question": "building, brickwork, a brick structure",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dteuk↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาคาร",
      "question": "building",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aa→ khaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไม่มีวัน",
      "question": "never (in the future)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เคย",
      "question": "(have you) ever, (as) before, did in the past, used to...",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheeuy→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไม่เคย",
      "question": "never (in the past)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ก๋วยเตี๋ยว",
      "question": "rice noodles",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[guay↗ dtiaao↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตะเกียบ",
      "question": "chopsticks",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dta↓ giiap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลอด",
      "question": "drinking straw",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laawt↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผ้า",
      "question": "cloth, material, fabric",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaa↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เช็ด",
      "question": "to wipe, to rub, to scrub",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chet↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตัว",
      "question": "(of a person) self, himself, herself, yourself, themselves, (things) itself",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtuaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผ้าเช็ดตัว",
      "question": "towel",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaa↘ chet↑ dtuaa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สะอาด",
      "question": "to clean",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sa↓ aat↓] (adj or verb)"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สบาย",
      "question": "(is) happy, comfortable, fine",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sa↓ baai→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "สะดวก",
      "question": "(is) convenient, comfortable",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sa↓ duaak↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใช้",
      "question": "to use, to employ or exploit an object, to utilize, to resort to, to implement",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chai↑]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "เวลา",
      "question": "(general) time (as in space and time)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waeh→ laa→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใช้เวลา",
      "question": "spend time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันเกิด",
      "question": "birthday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉลอง",
      "question": "celebrate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cha↓ laawng↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉลองวันเกิด",
      "question": "celebrate birthday",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หลัง",
      "question": "behind, following, at the rear",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lang↗]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลับ",
      "question": "to return or go back",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช่วง",
      "question": "period of time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ช่วงนี้",
      "question": "this period of time",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaang↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "โรค",
      "question": "disease, sickness, case",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hk↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระดับ",
      "question": "level, grade",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ dap↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระดับที่2",
      "question": "level 2",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ชาติ",
      "question": "national",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระดับชาติ",
      "question": "national level",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ dap↓ chaat↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แพร่",
      "question": "to publicize, broadcast, make public, disseminate",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phrae↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ระบาด",
      "question": "to break out (war or disease)",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ baat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "แพร่ระบาด",
      "question": "epidemic",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phrae↘ ra↑ baat↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "การระบาดของโรค",
      "question": "spread of a disease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาการ",
      "question": "symptoms",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aa→ gaan→]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาการของโรค",
      "question": "symptoms of the disease",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": ""
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผู้",
      "question": "person, human, case",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuu↘]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ป่วย",
      "question": "is sick",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpuay↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผู้ป่วย",
      "question": "patient, the sick",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuu↘ bpuay↓]"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "หอผู้ป่วย",
      "question": "hospital ward",
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haaw↗ phuu↘ bpuay↓]"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "language_1": "en",
  "subject": "Thai_language",
  "language_2": "th",
  "type": "BUTTON",
  "sentence": null
}
